[
    {
        "name": "General Knowledge",
        "questions": [
            { "question": "What is the capital of France?", "answer": "Paris" },
            { "question": "Who wrote 'Hamlet'?", "answer": "William Shakespeare" },
            { "question": "What is 5 + 7?", "answer": "12" },
            { "question": "In which year did the Titanic sink?", "answer": "1912" },
            { "question": "Who was the first man on the Moon?", "answer": "Neil Armstrong" },
            { "question": "Which planet is known as the Red Planet?", "answer": "Mars" },
            { "question": "What is the smallest country in the world?", "answer": "Vatican City" },
            { "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci" },
            { "question": "What is the longest river in the world?", "answer": "Nile River" },
            { "question": "Who discovered penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming" },
            { "question": "What element does 'O' represent on the periodic table?", "answer": "Oxygen" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Japan?", "answer": "Tokyo" },
            { "question": "Which animal is known as the king of the jungle?", "answer": "Lion" },
            { "question": "How many continents are there?", "answer": "7" },
            { "question": "What is the largest ocean in the world?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean" },
            { "question": "What is the hardest natural substance on Earth?", "answer": "Diamond" },
            { "question": "What year did World War I begin?", "answer": "1914" },
            { "question": "Who invented the telephone?", "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell" },
            { "question": "What is the chemical symbol for gold?", "answer": "Au" },
            { "question": "Who was the first President of the United States?", "answer": "George Washington" },
            { "question": "What is the longest-running TV show in the US?", "answer": "The Simpsons" },
            { "question": "In which city would you find the Colosseum?", "answer": "Rome" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Canada?", "answer": "Ottawa" },
            { "question": "Who painted the 'Starry Night'?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh" },
            { "question": "What is the name of the largest desert on Earth?", "answer": "Sahara" },
            { "question": "Which country is the largest by land area?", "answer": "Russia" },
            { "question": "In what year did the Berlin Wall fall?", "answer": "1989" },
            { "question": "Who wrote 'Pride and Prejudice'?", "answer": "Jane Austen" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Australia?", "answer": "Canberra" },
            { "question": "Which planet is the closest to the sun?", "answer": "Mercury" },
            { "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the world?", "answer": "Mount Everest" },
            { "question": "What is the national flower of Japan?", "answer": "Cherry Blossom" },
            { "question": "What is the main ingredient in guacamole?", "answer": "Avocado" },
            { "question": "In which year did the first manned moon landing occur?", "answer": "1969" },
            { "question": "What is the largest country in Africa?", "answer": "Algeria" },
            { "question": "What is the national animal of Australia?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
            { "question": "Which sea is the largest in the world?", "answer": "Philippine Sea" },
            { "question": "Who developed the theory of relativity?", "answer": "Albert Einstein" },
            { "question": "What is the name of the longest river in South America?", "answer": "Amazon River" },
            { "question": "What year did the first World War end?", "answer": "1918" },
            { "question": "What is the smallest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Stapes (in the ear)" },
            { "question": "Which ocean is the largest?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid" },
            { "question": "Who is known as the 'Father of Computers'?", "answer": "Charles Babbage" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasília" },
            { "question": "Which fruit is known for keeping the doctor away?", "answer": "Apple" },
            { "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart" },
            { "question": "What is the national bird of the United States?", "answer": "Bald Eagle" },
            { "question": "Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?", "answer": "Japan" },
            { "question": "In which year was the United Nations founded?", "answer": "1945" },
            { "question": "Which fruit has its seeds on the outside?", "answer": "Strawberry" },
            { "question": "What is the world's largest land mammal?", "answer": "African Elephant" },
            { "question": "What is the name of the longest river in Europe?", "answer": "Volga River" },
            { "question": "Which planet is the largest in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
            { "question": "What is the smallest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Mercury" },
            { "question": "Who was the first African-American President of the United States?", "answer": "Barack Obama" },
            { "question": "Which country is home to the Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Australia" },
            { "question": "What is the most common blood type?", "answer": "O+" },
            { "question": "Which fruit is the main ingredient in traditional British apple pie?", "answer": "Apple" },
            { "question": "Who invented the lightbulb?", "answer": "Thomas Edison" },
            { "question": "What is the largest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
            { "question": "Which famous ship sank in 1912?", "answer": "Titanic" },
            { "question": "What is the national currency of Japan?", "answer": "Yen" },
            { "question": "Which country is known for producing maple syrup?", "answer": "Canada" },
            { "question": "What does 'www' stand for in a web address?", "answer": "World Wide Web" },
            { "question": "Which human organ is capable of regenerating itself?", "answer": "Liver" },
            { "question": "Which city is known as the Big Apple?", "answer": "New York City" },
            { "question": "What is the highest-grossing movie of all time?", "answer": "Avatar" },
            { "question": "Who is the author of the Harry Potter book series?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling" },
            { "question": "What is the currency of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Pound Sterling" },
            { "question": "Which element has the chemical symbol 'Na'?", "answer": "Sodium" },
            { "question": "What is the most spoken language in the world?", "answer": "Mandarin Chinese" },
            { "question": "Which fruit is the main ingredient in the drink 'orange juice'?", "answer": "Orange" },
            { "question": "Which animal is the largest mammal in the world?", "answer": "Blue Whale" },
            { "question": "What is the capital of Italy?", "answer": "Rome" },
            { "question": "Which planet is closest to Earth?", "answer": "Venus" },
            { "question": "Which bird is famous for its ability to mimic human speech?", "answer": "Parrot" },
            { "question": "Which month has 28 days?", "answer": "All of them" },
            { "question": "Who invented the first successful airplane?", "answer": "Wright Brothers" },
            { "question": "What is the largest city in the world by population?", "answer": "Tokyo" },
            { "question": "Who is the Greek god of the sea?", "answer": "Poseidon" },
            { "question": "Which chemical element has the symbol 'Fe'?", "answer": "Iron" },
            { "question": "What is the largest island in the world?", "answer": "Greenland" },
            { "question": "What is the longest running Broadway show?", "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera" },
            { "question": "What is the smallest planet in the solar system?", "answer": "Mercury" },
            { "question": "What is the official language of Brazil?", "answer": "Portuguese" },
            { "question": "Which American state is known for its potatoes?", "answer": "Idaho" },
            { "question": "What is the name of the fictional wizard school in Harry Potter?", "answer": "Hogwarts" },
            { "question": "Which country is known for the Eiffel Tower?", "answer": "France" }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Science",
        "questions":  [
	    { "question": "What is the chemical symbol for water?", "answer": "H2O" },
	    { "question": "Who developed the theory of relativity?", "answer": "Albert Einstein" },
	    { "question": "What planet is known as the Red Planet?", "answer": "Mars" },
	    { "question": "What is the process by which plants make their own food?", "answer": "Photosynthesis" },
	    { "question": "What is the boiling point of water in degrees Celsius?", "answer": "100°C" },
	    { "question": "What is the smallest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Mercury" },
	    { "question": "What is the largest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
	    { "question": "What is the closest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun" },
	    { "question": "How many planets are in our solar system?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is the force that pulls objects toward the Earth?", "answer": "Gravity" },
	    { "question": "What gas do plants need for photosynthesis?", "answer": "Carbon Dioxide" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the scientist who discovered the law of gravity?", "answer": "Isaac Newton" },
	    { "question": "What is the largest organ in the human body?", "answer": "Skin" },
	    { "question": "What part of the body pumps blood?", "answer": "Heart" },
	    { "question": "What do we call a baby frog?", "answer": "Tadpole" },
	    { "question": "What is the most common gas in Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "Nitrogen" },
	    { "question": "What is the chemical symbol for oxygen?", "answer": "O2" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process by which water changes from a liquid to a gas?", "answer": "Evaporation" },
	    { "question": "What type of animal is a kangaroo?", "answer": "Marsupial" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the outermost layer of Earth?", "answer": "Crust" },
	    { "question": "Which planet is known for its beautiful rings?", "answer": "Saturn" },
	    { "question": "How many bones are there in the adult human body?", "answer": "206" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process by which rocks are broken down by wind and water?", "answer": "Erosion" },
	    { "question": "What is the boiling point of water in Fahrenheit?", "answer": "212°F" },
	    { "question": "What type of animal is a dolphin?", "answer": "Mammal" },
	    { "question": "What is the primary source of energy for Earth?", "answer": "The Sun" },
	    { "question": "What do we call the force that resists motion between two surfaces?", "answer": "Friction" },
	    { "question": "Which gas do humans breathe in to survive?", "answer": "Oxygen" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process where a solid turns directly into a gas?", "answer": "Sublimation" },
	    { "question": "Which planet is known as the 'Earth's twin'?", "answer": "Venus" },
	    { "question": "What is the center of an atom called?", "answer": "Nucleus" },
	    { "question": "What is the largest land animal?", "answer": "African Elephant" },
	    { "question": "What is the chemical formula for salt?", "answer": "NaCl" },
	    { "question": "What is the main function of the roots of a plant?", "answer": "Absorb water and nutrients" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the gas that makes up most of the air we breathe?", "answer": "Nitrogen" },
	    { "question": "What is the term for the spinning motion of a planet around its axis?", "answer": "Rotation" },
	    { "question": "What is the term for the path that a planet takes around the sun?", "answer": "Orbit" },
	    { "question": "What are the three states of matter?", "answer": "Solid, liquid, gas" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process by which a liquid turns into a solid?", "answer": "Freezing" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the large body of water that covers 71% of the Earth's surface?", "answer": "Ocean" },
	    { "question": "What is the most famous volcano that erupted in 79 AD?", "answer": "Mount Vesuvius" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process that changes water into ice?", "answer": "Freezing" },
	    { "question": "What is the force that pushes an object forward when it is in motion?", "answer": "Thrust" },
	    { "question": "What type of plant is known for its ability to store water in its leaves?", "answer": "Cactus" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the closest galaxy to the Milky Way?", "answer": "Andromeda" },
	    { "question": "What do we call a scientist who studies the stars and planets?", "answer": "Astronomer" },
	    { "question": "What planet is closest to the Sun?", "answer": "Mercury" },
	    { "question": "What is the largest living animal on Earth?", "answer": "Blue Whale" },
	    { "question": "What is the name of the process by which plants release water vapor?", "answer": "Transpiration" },
	    { "question": "What is the main function of the human lungs?", "answer": "Oxygenate blood" },
	    { "question": "What is the process by which a caterpillar becomes a butterfly?", "answer": "Metamorphosis" }
    ]

    },
    {
        "name": "Medicine",
        "questions": [
    { "question": "What is the largest organ in the human body?", "answer": "Skin" },
    { "question": "How many bones are in the adult human body?", "answer": "206" },
    { "question": "What is the primary function of red blood cells?", "answer": "Transport oxygen" },
    { "question": "Which part of the brain controls breathing?", "answer": "Medulla Oblongata" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the bone that protects the brain?", "answer": "Skull" },
    { "question": "What part of the human body produces insulin?", "answer": "Pancreas" },
    { "question": "What is the main function of the liver?", "answer": "Detoxify chemicals and metabolize drugs" },
    { "question": "Which organ is primarily responsible for digestion?", "answer": "Stomach" },
    { "question": "How many chambers does the human heart have?", "answer": "4" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the fluid that cushions and protects the brain and spinal cord?", "answer": "Cerebrospinal fluid" },
    { "question": "What type of blood vessel carries blood away from the heart?", "answer": "Arteries" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the tube that connects the throat to the stomach?", "answer": "Esophagus" },
    { "question": "What is the main function of the kidneys?", "answer": "Filter waste from the blood" },
    { "question": "What part of the human body is responsible for the sense of smell?", "answer": "Nose" },
    { "question": "What is the largest artery in the human body?", "answer": "Aorta" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the hormone that regulates blood sugar?", "answer": "Insulin" },
    { "question": "Which part of the brain is responsible for memory?", "answer": "Hippocampus" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the structure in the eye that focuses light?", "answer": "Lens" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the voice box?", "answer": "Larynx" },
    { "question": "What is the average number of teeth in an adult human mouth?", "answer": "32" },
    { "question": "Which part of the nervous system controls involuntary functions?", "answer": "Autonomic nervous system" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the blood vessel that carries blood back to the heart?", "answer": "Vein" },
    { "question": "What type of muscle is found in the heart?", "answer": "Cardiac muscle" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the protective layer that surrounds the heart?", "answer": "Pericardium" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the largest part of the brain?", "answer": "Cerebrum" },
    { "question": "Which bone is the longest bone in the human body?", "answer": "Femur" },
    { "question": "Which organ is responsible for the production of bile?", "answer": "Liver" },
    { "question": "What is the primary function of the lungs?", "answer": "Oxygenate blood and remove carbon dioxide" },
    { "question": "What is the medical term for the kneecap?", "answer": "Patella" },
    { "question": "Which system in the human body regulates hormones?", "answer": "Endocrine system" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the tube that connects the middle ear to the throat?", "answer": "Eustachian tube" },
    { "question": "What is the main function of the small intestine?", "answer": "Absorb nutrients from food" },
    { "question": "What part of the body contains the most bones?", "answer": "Hands and feet" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the cartilage that cushions the knee joint?", "answer": "Meniscus" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the process of converting food into energy?", "answer": "Metabolism" },
    { "question": "What type of cell is responsible for immune response?", "answer": "White blood cell" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the structure that connects muscles to bones?", "answer": "Tendon" },
    { "question": "Which body system is responsible for transporting nutrients, gases, and wastes?", "answer": "Circulatory system" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the fluid found in the joints that lubricates and reduces friction?", "answer": "Synovial fluid" },
    { "question": "What is the term for a condition where bones become weak and brittle?", "answer": "Osteoporosis" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the upper part of the human digestive tract?", "answer": "Mouth" },
    { "question": "Which part of the brain is responsible for regulating body temperature?", "answer": "Hypothalamus" },
    { "question": "What is the medical term for the windpipe?", "answer": "Trachea" },
    { "question": "What part of the human body filters blood to produce urine?", "answer": "Kidneys" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the bone at the base of the spine?", "answer": "Coccyx" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the protective covering around the brain?", "answer": "Meninges" },
    { "question": "Which blood type is known as the universal donor?", "answer": "O negative" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the body system responsible for movement?", "answer": "Muscular system" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the ability of muscles to contract and shorten?", "answer": "Contractility" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the outermost layer of skin?", "answer": "Epidermis" },
    { "question": "Which part of the body is responsible for producing red blood cells?", "answer": "Bone marrow" },
    { "question": "What is the term for the process by which the body maintains a stable internal environment?", "answer": "Homeostasis" }
]

    },
    {
        "name": "Geography",
        "questions": [
    { "question": "What is the capital of France?", "answer": "Paris" },
    { "question": "Which continent is the Sahara Desert located on?", "answer": "Africa" },
    { "question": "What is the longest river in the world?", "answer": "Amazon River" },
    { "question": "Which country has the most volcanoes?", "answer": "Indonesia" },
    { "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the world?", "answer": "Mount Everest" },
    { "question": "Which ocean is the largest?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean" },
    { "question": "What is the smallest country in the world by land area?", "answer": "Vatican City" },
    { "question": "Which river flows through Egypt?", "answer": "Nile River" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Japan?", "answer": "Tokyo" },
    { "question": "Which continent is known as 'The Dark Continent'?", "answer": "Africa" },
    { "question": "Which country is known as the Land of the Rising Sun?", "answer": "Japan" },
    { "question": "What is the largest desert in the world?", "answer": "Antarctic Desert" },
    { "question": "Which country is home to the Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Australia" },
    { "question": "Which U.S. state is known as the 'Sunshine State'?", "answer": "Florida" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Canada?", "answer": "Ottawa" },
    { "question": "Which city is known as the 'Eternal City'?", "answer": "Rome" },
    { "question": "Which country has the most time zones?", "answer": "Russia" },
    { "question": "What is the largest island in the world?", "answer": "Greenland" },
    { "question": "Which country is bordered by both the Mediterranean Sea and the Red Sea?", "answer": "Egypt" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasília" },
    { "question": "Which city is known as the 'Big Apple'?", "answer": "New York City" },
    { "question": "Which country is the largest by land area?", "answer": "Russia" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the longest mountain range in the world?", "answer": "Andes" },
    { "question": "Which country is the most populous in the world?", "answer": "China" },
    { "question": "Which river is the longest in Africa?", "answer": "Nile River" },
    { "question": "Which country is both in Europe and Asia?", "answer": "Turkey" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Australia?", "answer": "Canberra" },
    { "question": "Which country is known for its pyramids?", "answer": "Egypt" },
    { "question": "What is the largest country in Africa by area?", "answer": "Algeria" },
    { "question": "Which country has the most islands?", "answer": "Sweden" },
    { "question": "Which country is home to the famous Machu Picchu ruins?", "answer": "Peru" },
    { "question": "What is the largest country in South America?", "answer": "Brazil" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "London" },
    { "question": "Which sea is the largest by surface area?", "answer": "Philippine Sea" },
    { "question": "Which mountain is known as the 'Matterhorn'?", "answer": "The Matterhorn" },
    { "question": "Which country is home to the Amazon Rainforest?", "answer": "Brazil" },
    { "question": "Which country has the most pyramids?", "answer": "Sudan" },
    { "question": "Which country is the island of Madagascar located off of?", "answer": "Mozambique" },
    { "question": "Which continent is home to the most countries?", "answer": "Africa" },
    { "question": "Which is the smallest continent by land area?", "answer": "Australia" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul" },
    { "question": "What is the currency of Japan?", "answer": "Yen" },
    { "question": "What country has the most volcanoes in the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Indonesia" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Argentina?", "answer": "Buenos Aires" },
    { "question": "What ocean is to the west of the United States?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean" },
    { "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid" },
    { "question": "Which country is home to the famous Inca city of Cusco?", "answer": "Peru" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the largest river in Asia?", "answer": "Yangtze River" },
    { "question": "Which country is known for the Eiffel Tower?", "answer": "France" }
]
    },
    {
    "name": "Animals",
    "questions": [
        { "question": "What is the largest land animal?", "answer": "African Elephant" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known as the 'King of the Jungle'?", "answer": "Lion" },
        { "question": "What is the fastest land animal?", "answer": "Cheetah" },
        { "question": "Which animal is the largest mammal?", "answer": "Blue Whale" },
        { "question": "What is the only mammal capable of true flight?", "answer": "Bat" },
        { "question": "What is the most intelligent animal on Earth?", "answer": "Dolphin" },
        { "question": "Which bird is known for its colorful tail feathers and elaborate courtship dance?", "answer": "Peacock" },
        { "question": "What is the fastest bird in the world?", "answer": "Peregrine Falcon" },
        { "question": "Which animal has the longest lifespan?", "answer": "Bowhead Whale" },
        { "question": "What is the largest species of shark?", "answer": "Whale Shark" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for changing its color to blend into its surroundings?", "answer": "Chameleon" },
        { "question": "What is the smallest mammal by size?", "answer": "Bumblebee Bat" },
        { "question": "Which animal is famous for having a long neck?", "answer": "Giraffe" },
        { "question": "What is the most dangerous animal in the world?", "answer": "Mosquito" },
        { "question": "Which animal can sleep for up to three years?", "answer": "Snail" },
        { "question": "What animal is known to have a natural 'sixth sense' to detect earthquakes?", "answer": "Dogs" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known to have the strongest bite force?", "answer": "Crocodile" },
        { "question": "What is the only bird that can fly backwards?", "answer": "Hummingbird" },
        { "question": "Which species of bear is found only in China?", "answer": "Giant Panda" },
        { "question": "Which mammal is capable of true hibernation?", "answer": "Ground Squirrel" },
        { "question": "What animal is known to have the best sense of hearing?", "answer": "Elephant" },
        { "question": "Which animal is famous for building dams in rivers?", "answer": "Beaver" },
        { "question": "What is the fastest aquatic animal?", "answer": "Black Marlin" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for its large ears and ability to fly?", "answer": "Bat" },
        { "question": "What is the only mammal that can fly?", "answer": "Bat" },
        { "question": "What is the most poisonous animal in the world?", "answer": "Box Jellyfish" },
        { "question": "Which animal is the symbol of the WWF?", "answer": "Giant Panda" },
        { "question": "Which animal is capable of regenerating its limbs?", "answer": "Axolotl" },
        { "question": "What animal has the largest eyes?", "answer": "Colossal Squid" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for its ability to produce venom?", "answer": "Snake" },
        { "question": "What animal has the longest migration distance?", "answer": "Arctic Tern" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for living in colonies and having a queen?", "answer": "Ant" },
        { "question": "What is the largest species of tiger?", "answer": "Siberian Tiger" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for being the most poisonous frog?", "answer": "Golden Poison Dart Frog" },
        { "question": "What is the fastest growing plant in the world?", "answer": "Bamboo" },
        { "question": "Which animal is capable of changing its sex?", "answer": "Clownfish" },
        { "question": "What animal has the longest tongue in relation to its size?", "answer": "Chameleon" },
        { "question": "Which animal has the most legs?", "answer": "Millipede" },
        { "question": "Which bird is the largest in the world?", "answer": "Ostrich" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the largest living reptile?", "answer": "Saltwater Crocodile" },
        { "question": "Which animal has the longest neck?", "answer": "Giraffe" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known to have a 'saber-tooth' tooth?", "answer": "Saber-Toothed Tiger" },
        { "question": "What is the largest rodent in the world?", "answer": "Capybara" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known to make the loudest sound?", "answer": "Blue Whale" },
        { "question": "What is the only species of penguin that lives in the wild in Africa?", "answer": "African Penguin" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for its intelligence and ability to use tools?", "answer": "Chimpanzee" },
        { "question": "Which mammal is known to lay eggs?", "answer": "Platypus" },
        { "question": "What is the smallest bird in the world?", "answer": "Bee Hummingbird" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for its large tusks?", "answer": "Elephant" },
        { "question": "What is the most populous animal on Earth?", "answer": "Ant" },
        { "question": "Which animal can regenerate its tail if lost?", "answer": "Gecko" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known for carrying its young in a pouch?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
        { "question": "What animal is known as the 'ship of the desert'?", "answer": "Camel" },
        { "question": "Which bird is the national symbol of the United States?", "answer": "Bald Eagle" },
        { "question": "What is the largest snake in the world?", "answer": "Green Anaconda" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Lizard" },
        { "question": "Which marine creature has three hearts?", "answer": "Octopus" },
        { "question": "What animal is known for its impressive memory?", "answer": "Elephant" },
        { "question": "Which bird is famous for imitating sounds?", "answer": "Lyrebird" },
        { "question": "Which animal is known to live in a den?", "answer": "Fox" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the fastest reptile?", "answer": "Spiny-Tailed Iguana" },
        { "question": "Which animal is considered the largest carnivore?", "answer": "Polar Bear" },
        { "question": "Which fish is capable of producing electricity?", "answer": "Electric Eel" },
        { "question": "Which insect is known for its ability to glow?", "answer": "Firefly" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a tarantula?", "answer": "Spider" },
        { "question": "What is the only marsupial found in North America?", "answer": "Opossum" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a monarch?", "answer": "Butterfly" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a pufferfish?", "answer": "Fish" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a meerkat?", "answer": "Mongoose" },
        { "question": "What type of animal is a corgi?", "answer": "Dog" }
    ]
},
{
	"name": "AlphaBites",
 	"questions": [
    { "question": "What 'P' is a type of bird that can't fly?", "answer": "Penguin" },
    { "question": "What 'A' is a type of fruit that grows on a tree?", "answer": "Apple" },
    { "question": "What 'B' is a type of animal that lives in a burrow?", "answer": "Badger" },
    { "question": "What 'B' is a type of insect known for making honey?", "answer": "Bee" },
    { "question": "What 'D' is a type of animal that quacks?", "answer": "Duck" },
    { "question": "What 'F' is a type of animal known for hopping?", "answer": "Frog" },
    { "question": "What 'G' is a type of fruit that is green and sour?", "answer": "Gooseberry" },
    { "question": "What 'H' is a bird that can be found in the UK?", "answer": "Heron" },
    { "question": "What 'K' is a type of bird with a colorful beak?", "answer": "Kingfisher" },
    { "question": "What 'L' is a type of animal that lives in a pride?", "answer": "Lion" },
    { "question": "What 'G' is a type of animal known for its long neck?", "answer": "Giraffe" },
    { "question": "What 'N' is a type of animal that tends to come out at night time?", "answer": "Nocturnal" },
    { "question": "What 'O' is a type of fruit that is orange?", "answer": "Orange" },
    { "question": "What 'P' is a bird that loves the ocean?", "answer": "Penguin" },
    { "question": "What 'Q' is a type of bird with a colorful tail?", "answer": "Quail" },
    { "question": "What 'R' is a type of animal with large, floppy ears?", "answer": "Rabbit" },
    { "question": "What 'T' is a fruit that is a favorite for making ketchup?", "answer": "Tomato" },
    { "question": "What 'F' is a type of tree that has needles instead of leaves?", "answer": "Fir" },
    { "question": "What 'S' is a farm animal that produces wool?", "answer": "Sheep" },
    { "question": "What 'Z' is an animal that looks like a donkey and lives in Africa?", "answer": "Zebra" },
    { "question": "What 'M' is a large mammal found in Africa?", "answer": "Monkey" },
    { "question": "What 'P' is a type of tree that grows in the UK?", "answer": "Pine" },
    { "question": "What 'R' is a type of fruit that's commonly eaten as a dessert?", "answer": "Raspberry" },
    { "question": "What 'B' is an insect that produces honey?", "answer": "Bee" },
    { "question": "What 'P' is a type of bear that lives in cold climates?", "answer": "Polar Bear" },
    { "question": "What 'L' is a color that comes from some flowers?", "answer": "Lavender" },
    { "question": "What 'C' is a pet animal with fur?", "answer": "Cat" },
    { "question": "What 'K' is a type of vegetable grown in gardens?", "answer": "Kale" },
    { "question": "What 'C' is a type of vegetable grown in gardens, it is orange in colour?", "answer": "Carrort" },
    { "question": "What 'C' is a type of leafy vegetable grown in gardens, it is green in colour?", "answer": "Cabbage" },
    { "question": "What 'T' is a sweet treat made from sugar?", "answer": "Toffee" },
    { "question": "What 'A' is a color often seen in autumn?", "answer": "Amber" },
    { "question": "What 'C' is a popular British chocolate maker?", "answer": "Cadbury" },
    { "question": "What 'F' is a classic children's book written by Roald Dahl?", "answer": "Fantastic Mr. Fox" },
    { "question": "What 'E' is an animal with a long trunk?", "answer": "Elephant" },
    { "question": "What 'N' is the sound a horse makes?", "answer": "Neigh" },
    { "question": "What 'C' is the name of a farmyard animal that often clucks?", "answer": "Chicken" },
    { "question": "What 'BB' is a famous pirate?", "answer": "Black Beard" },
    { "question": "What 'S' is a type of animal known for its slow movement and shell?", "answer": "Snail" },
    { "question": "What 'K' is an animal that can be found in Australia and is famous for its jump?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
    { "question": "What 'O' is a type of animal that lives under the sea and has eight tentacles?", "answer": "Octopus" },
    { "question": "What 'B' is a type of insect that makes a buzzing sound and helps pollinate flowers?", "answer": "Bee" },
    { "question": "What 'M' is a large mammal known for its tusks, and hariy or wooly skin?", "answer": "Mammoth" },
    { "question": "What 'B' is a type of animal known for its large size and strength?", "answer": "Bear" },
    { "question": "What 'F' is a type of small animal known for its ability to hop?", "answer": "Frog" },
    { "question": "What 'I' is a type of animal known for its long, skinny body and ability to climb?", "answer": "Iguana" },
    { "question": "What 'P' is a type of bird known for its intelligence and ability to mimic sounds?", "answer": "Parrot" },
    { "question": "What 'O' is a type of tree that produces acorns?", "answer": "Oak" },
    { "question": "What 'P' is a tree that grows in a tropical climate and produces a large fruit?", "answer": "Papaya" },
    { "question": "What 'G' is an animal that is known for its long neck?", "answer": "Giraffe" },
    { "question": "What 'W' is a large animal that lives in the ocean?", "answer": "Whale" }
    ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Maths",
        "questions": [
	    { "question": "What is 2 + 5?", "answer": "7" },
	    { "question": "What is 9 + 8?", "answer": "17" }, 
	    { "question": "What is 15 - 6?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 7 + 6?", "answer": "13" },
  	    { "question": "What is 14 - 4?", "answer": "10" },
	    { "question": "What is 12 + 3?", "answer": "15" },
	    { "question": "What is 17 - 9?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 6 + 7?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 11 + 5?", "answer": "16" },
	    { "question": "What is 18 - 7?", "answer": "11" },
	    { "question": "What is 3 + 10?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 8 + 5?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 10 + 7?", "answer": "17" },
	    { "question": "What is 14 - 3?", "answer": "11" },
	    { "question": "What is 9 + 4?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 16 - 8?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 7 + 9?", "answer": "16" },
	    { "question": "What is 13 - 6?", "answer": "7" },
	    { "question": "What is 5 + 4?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 8 + 8?", "answer": "16" },
	    { "question": "What is 12 - 5?", "answer": "7" },
	    { "question": "What is 6 + 3?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 17 - 8?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 4 + 10?", "answer": "14" },
	    { "question": "What is 15 - 7?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 11 + 3?", "answer": "14" },
	    { "question": "What is 16 - 9?", "answer": "7" },
	    { "question": "What is 6 + 10?", "answer": "16" },
	    { "question": "What is 18 - 4?", "answer": "14" },
	    { "question": "What is 9 + 6?", "answer": "15" },
	    { "question": "What is 12 - 4?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 3 + 8?", "answer": "11" },
	    { "question": "What is 5 + 9?", "answer": "14" },
	    { "question": "What is 10 - 3?", "answer": "7" },
	    { "question": "What is 7 + 4?", "answer": "11" },
	    { "question": "What is 14 - 9?", "answer": "5" },
	    { "question": "What is 11 + 6?", "answer": "17" },
	    { "question": "What is 13 - 4?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 8 + 3?", "answer": "11" },
	    { "question": "What is 9 - 5?", "answer": "4" },
	    { "question": "What is 6 + 2?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 17 - 4?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 12 + 5?", "answer": "17" },
	    { "question": "What is 4 + 11?", "answer": "15" },
	    { "question": "What is 16 - 7?", "answer": "9" },
	    { "question": "What is 7 + 3?", "answer": "10" },
	    { "question": "What is 13 - 5?", "answer": "8" },
	    { "question": "What is 5 + 12?", "answer": "17" },
	    { "question": "What is 10 - 6?", "answer": "4" },
	    { "question": "What is 8 + 7?", "answer": "15" },
	    { "question": "What is 6 - 2?", "answer": "4" },
	    { "question": "What is 9 + 4?", "answer": "13" },
	    { "question": "What is 15 - 5?", "answer": "10" }, 
	    { "question": "What is 14 + 2?", "answer": "16" }, 
	    { "question": "What is 11 - 7?", "answer": "4" },
	    { "question": "What is 8 - 3?", "answer": "5" }
	]
     },
    {
        "name": "Times Tables",
        "questions": [
    { "question": "What is 8 x 3?", "answer": "24" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 7?", "answer": "35" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 10?", "answer": "20" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 1?", "answer": "12" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 5?", "answer": "20" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 4?", "answer": "36" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 6?", "answer": "42" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 11?", "answer": "33" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 7?", "answer": "14" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 10?", "answer": "60" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 3?", "answer": "30" },
    { "question": "What is 1 x 12?", "answer": "12" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 5?", "answer": "25" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 8?", "answer": "32" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 2?", "answer": "18" },
    { "question": "What is 11 x 2?", "answer": "22" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 3?", "answer": "18" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 8?", "answer": "24" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 9?", "answer": "108" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 11?", "answer": "66" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 5?", "answer": "10" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 7?", "answer": "56" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 9?", "answer": "63" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 1?", "answer": "3" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 12?", "answer": "60" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 4?", "answer": "24" },
    { "question": "What is 11 x 6?", "answer": "66" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 3?", "answer": "36" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 2?", "answer": "14" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 9?", "answer": "90" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 6?", "answer": "54" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 2?", "answer": "8" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 7?", "answer": "42" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 3?", "answer": "15" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 9?", "answer": "27" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 4?", "answer": "8" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 10?", "answer": "80" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 6?", "answer": "60" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 5?", "answer": "60" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 11?", "answer": "77" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 11?", "answer": "110" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 2?", "answer": "24" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 8?", "answer": "72" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 8?", "answer": "40" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 11?", "answer": "44" },
    { "question": "What is 1 x 6?", "answer": "6" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 2?", "answer": "16" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 9?", "answer": "18" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 6?", "answer": "72" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 10?", "answer": "30" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 4?", "answer": "20" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 12?", "answer": "120" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 9?", "answer": "36" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 10?", "answer": "70" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 12?", "answer": "72" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 2?", "answer": "20" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 6?", "answer": "12" },
    { "question": "What is 11 x 10?", "answer": "110" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 7?", "answer": "21" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 10?", "answer": "90" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 4?", "answer": "48" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 6?", "answer": "48" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 8?", "answer": "48" },
    { "question": "What is 1 x 11?", "answer": "11" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 3?", "answer": "12" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 4?", "answer": "12" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 3?", "answer": "21" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 10?", "answer": "120" },
    { "question": "What is 1 x 9?", "answer": "9" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 11?", "answer": "88" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 11?", "answer": "22" },
    { "question": "What is 10 x 5?", "answer": "50" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 5?", "answer": "30" },
    { "question": "What is 4 x 6?", "answer": "24" },
    { "question": "What is 11 x 12?", "answer": "132" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 5?", "answer": "15" },
    { "question": "What is 5 x 6?", "answer": "30" },
    { "question": "What is 1 x 5?", "answer": "5" },
    { "question": "What is 7 x 4?", "answer": "28" },
    { "question": "What is 9 x 12?", "answer": "108" },
    { "question": "What is 8 x 9?", "answer": "72" },
    { "question": "What is 2 x 3?", "answer": "6" },
    { "question": "What is 6 x 9?", "answer": "54" },
    { "question": "What is 12 x 11?", "answer": "132" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 12?", "answer": "36" },
    { "question": "What is 3 x 10?", "answer": "30" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 1?", "answer": "1" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 9?", "answer": "36" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 4?", "answer": "36" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 10?", "answer": "60" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 5?", "answer": "35" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 6?", "answer": "60" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 11?", "answer": "121" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 5?", "answer": "20" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 7?", "answer": "35" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 10?", "answer": "90" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 8?", "answer": "88" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 4?", "answer": "44" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 11?", "answer": "11" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 4?", "answer": "48" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 6?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 8?", "answer": "32" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 3?", "answer": "15" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 11?", "answer": "22" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 1?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 11?", "answer": "55" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 12?", "answer": "72" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 3?", "answer": "36" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 7?", "answer": "14" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 12?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 8?", "answer": "56" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 10?", "answer": "20" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 7?", "answer": "70" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 3?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 5?", "answer": "15" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 11?", "answer": "99" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 11?", "answer": "66" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 2?", "answer": "16" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 6?", "answer": "72" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 8?", "answer": "48" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 10?", "answer": "50" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 1?", "answer": "2" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 2?", "answer": "14" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 10?", "answer": "120" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 8?", "answer": "16" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 1?", "answer": "9" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 10?", "answer": "40" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 8?", "answer": "64" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 1?", "answer": "3" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 8?", "answer": "8" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 7?", "answer": "42" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 6?", "answer": "54" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 8?", "answer": "72" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 7?", "answer": "77" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 9?", "answer": "108" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 6?", "answer": "42" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 10?", "answer": "100" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 7?", "answer": "28" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 6?", "answer": "6" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 1?", "answer": "6" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 5?", "answer": "5" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 2?", "answer": "8" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 5?", "answer": "30" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 1?", "answer": "8" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 5?", "answer": "40" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 8?", "answer": "96" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 5?", "answer": "60" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 5?", "answer": "45" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 9?", "answer": "90" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 8?", "answer": "80" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 9?", "answer": "54" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 1?", "answer": "10" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 2?", "answer": "6" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 1?", "answer": "4" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 3?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 2?", "answer": "2" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 1?", "answer": "7" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 7?", "answer": "21" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 12?", "answer": "96" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 7?", "answer": "84" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 12?", "answer": "48" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 7?", "answer": "49" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 2?", "answer": "22" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 6?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 3?", "answer": "6" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 4?", "answer": "32" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 12?", "answer": "60" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 7?", "answer": "56" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 7?", "answer": "7" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 10?", "answer": "80" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 11?", "answer": "33" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 6?", "answer": "48" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 9?", "answer": "72" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 12?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 4?", "answer": "16" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 7?", "answer": "63" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 9?", "answer": "81" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 4?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 11?", "answer": "110" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 4?", "answer": "28" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 3?", "answer": "3" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 3?", "answer": "18" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 8?", "answer": "40" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 11?", "answer": "132" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 9?", "answer": "45" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 2?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 5?", "answer": "50" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 12?", "answer": "120" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 5?", "answer": "55" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 9?", "answer": "99" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 9?", "answer": "9" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 11?", "answer": "77" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 6?", "answer": "36" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 1?", "answer": "5" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 10?", "answer": "110" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 2?", "answer": "20" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 2?", "answer": "4" },
{ "question": "What is 6 x 2?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 5?", "answer": "25" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 9?", "answer": "63" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 12?", "answer": "36" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 3?", "answer": "27" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 1?", "answer": "11" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 4?", "answer": "8" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 4?", "answer": "20" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 3?", "answer": "30" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 9?", "answer": "18" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 10?", "answer": "70" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 3?", "answer": "21" },
{ "question": "What is 2 x 5?", "answer": "10" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 10?", "answer": "10" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 12?", "answer": "108" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 4?", "answer": "12" },
{ "question": "What is 10 x 4?", "answer": "40" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 3?", "answer": "33" },
{ "question": "What is 7 x 12?", "answer": "84" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 3?", "answer": "9" },
{ "question": "What is 9 x 2?", "answer": "18" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 2?", "answer": "10" },
{ "question": "What is 4 x 11?", "answer": "44" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 9?", "answer": "27" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 6?", "answer": "66" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 6?", "answer": "18" },
{ "question": "What is 5 x 6?", "answer": "30" },
{ "question": "What is 3 x 8?", "answer": "24" },
{ "question": "What is 12 x 12?", "answer": "144" },
{ "question": "What is 1 x 4?", "answer": "4" },
{ "question": "What is 8 x 11?", "answer": "88" },
{ "question": "What is 11 x 12?", "answer": "132" }
      ]	
    },
	{
    "name": "Space",
    "questions": [
        { "question": "What is the largest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known as the 'Red Planet'?", "answer": "Mars" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the galaxy we live in?", "answer": "The Milky Way" },
        { "question": "What is the closest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun" },
        { "question": "What is the smallest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Mercury" },
        { "question": "Which planet has rings made of ice and rock?", "answer": "Saturn" },
        { "question": "What is the hottest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Venus" },
        { "question": "What do we call a giant ball of gas that produces light and heat in space?", "answer": "A star" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the moon that orbits Earth?", "answer": "The Moon" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the planet famous for its big red storm?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
        { "question": "What force keeps planets in orbit around the Sun?", "answer": "Gravity" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the dwarf planet located in the Kuiper Belt?", "answer": "Pluto" },
        { "question": "What do we call the path that planets follow around the Sun?", "answer": "An orbit" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known as the 'blue planet'?", "answer": "Earth" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the spacecraft that first landed humans on the Moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the largest volcano in our solar system?", "answer": "Olympus Mons" },
        { "question": "On which planet can you find Olympus Mons?", "answer": "Mars" },
        { "question": "What do astronauts wear to survive in space?", "answer": "A spacesuit" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the telescope that orbits Earth and takes pictures of space?", "answer": "The Hubble Space Telescope" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a shooting star?", "answer": "A meteor" },
        { "question": "What is a black hole?", "answer": "A place in space where gravity is so strong that not even light can escape" },
        { "question": "What is the closest planet to the Sun?", "answer": "Mercury" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the second-largest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Saturn" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the boundary around a black hole?", "answer": "The event horizon" },
        { "question": "What are the small rocky bodies that orbit the Sun called?", "answer": "Asteroids" },
        { "question": "What is a comet made of?", "answer": "Ice, dust, and rock" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the galaxy closest to the Milky Way?", "answer": "Andromeda Galaxy" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a group of stars forming a pattern in the sky?", "answer": "A constellation" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the force that keeps us on the ground?", "answer": "Gravity" },
        { "question": "Which planet is tilted so much that it rotates on its side?", "answer": "Uranus" },
        { "question": "What do we call the explosion of a dying star?", "answer": "A supernova" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the rover currently exploring Mars?", "answer": "Perseverance" },
        { "question": "Which planet is farthest from the Sun?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "What is the coldest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the bright band of light made up of millions of stars in the night sky?", "answer": "The Milky Way" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the layer of gases that surrounds Earth?", "answer": "The atmosphere" },
        { "question": "What is a space rock that lands on Earth called?", "answer": "A meteorite" },
        { "question": "What do we call the time it takes for Earth to orbit the Sun once?", "answer": "A year" },
        { "question": "What is the main component of the Sun?", "answer": "Hydrogen" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the largest moon of Jupiter?", "answer": "Ganymede" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the spacecraft that took the first close-up pictures of Pluto?", "answer": "New Horizons" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the red supergiant star in the Orion constellation?", "answer": "Betelgeuse" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known for its strong winds and dark blue color?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the international space station orbiting Earth?", "answer": "The International Space Station (ISS)" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the spinning of a planet on its axis?", "answer": "Rotation" },
        { "question": "What is the term for when a planet travels around the Sun?", "answer": "Revolution" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the boundary of the Sun’s influence in the solar system?", "answer": "The heliopause" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the distance light travels in one year?", "answer": "A light-year" },
        { "question": "Which planet has the Great Dark Spot?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the tiny moons orbiting Mars?", "answer": "Phobos and Deimos" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the glowing halo of gas around the Sun during a solar eclipse?", "answer": "The corona" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the first satellite sent into space?", "answer": "Sputnik 1" },
        { "question": "Who was the first human to travel into space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a group of stars, gas, and dust held together by gravity?", "answer": "A galaxy" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known as Earth's twin?", "answer": "Venus" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the first American astronaut to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Neil Armstrong" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the largest moon in the solar system?", "answer": "Ganymede" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the telescope set to replace the Hubble Space Telescope?", "answer": "James Webb Space Telescope" },
        { "question": "Which planet is famous for its Great Red Spot?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the faint outer shadow of the Earth or Moon?", "answer": "The penumbra" },
        { "question": "What is the main reason we experience seasons on Earth?", "answer": "Earth's tilt on its axis" },
        { "question": "Which planet has a day that is longer than its year?", "answer": "Venus" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the belt of asteroids located between Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "The Asteroid Belt" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the closest dwarf planet to the Sun?", "answer": "Ceres" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a star that suddenly increases in brightness and then fades?", "answer": "A nova" },
        { "question": "What are the bright streaks of light in the sky called, caused by meteoroids burning up in Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "Meteors" },
        { "question": "What is the coldest place in our solar system?", "answer": "Triton (Neptune's moon)" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the first woman to travel to space?", "answer": "Valentina Tereshkova" },
        { "question": "What do we call the study of space and celestial objects?", "answer": "Astronomy" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the explosion at the end of a massive star's life?", "answer": "Supernova" },
        { "question": "What is the faint light seen around the Sun during a total solar eclipse?", "answer": "The corona" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Mars' largest volcano?", "answer": "Olympus Mons" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the layer of gases surrounding a planet?", "answer": "Atmosphere" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the swirling clouds of dust and gas where stars are born?", "answer": "Nebula" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the area around a planet where its gravity is strong enough to hold onto its moons?", "answer": "Hill Sphere" },
        { "question": "What is the shape of the Milky Way galaxy?", "answer": "Spiral" },
        { "question": "Which planet has the most moons?", "answer": "Saturn" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the second man to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin" },
        { "question": "What do we call a massive system of stars, dust, and dark matter held together by gravity?", "answer": "A galaxy" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the boundary around a black hole beyond which nothing can escape?", "answer": "The event horizon" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the phenomenon where light bends around massive objects like galaxies?", "answer": "Gravitational lensing" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the invisible force that holds planets and stars together?", "answer": "Gravity" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the region of space where a planet's magnetic field dominates?", "answer": "Magnetosphere" },
        { "question": "What is the smallest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Mercury" },
        { "question": "What is the hottest star color?", "answer": "Blue" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the Sun’s outermost layer?", "answer": "The corona" },
        { "question": "Which planet is called the 'Ice Giant' along with Uranus?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "What is the bright spot on Neptune called?", "answer": "The Great Dark Spot" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a rock in space before it enters Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "Meteoroid" },
        { "question": "Which planet is named after the Roman god of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known for having the shortest day?", "answer": "Jupiter" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the process where a star forms from a collapsing cloud of gas and dust?", "answer": "Star formation" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the glowing trail left by a comet as it approaches the Sun?", "answer": "Comet's tail" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the region of space filled with icy bodies beyond Neptune?", "answer": "The Kuiper Belt" },
        { "question": "What is the term for a planet located outside our solar system?", "answer": "Exoplanet" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the smallest and closest planet to the Sun?", "answer": "Mercury" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the first human-made object to reach interstellar space?", "answer": "Voyager 1" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the space agency responsible for missions like Apollo 11?", "answer": "NASA" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known as the 'Morning Star' or 'Evening Star'?", "answer": "Venus" },
        { "question": "What is the term for the process that powers stars like the Sun?", "answer": "Nuclear fusion" }
    ]
},
	{
    "name": "Christmas",
    "questions": [
        { "question": "What is the name of the baby whose birth is celebrated at Christmas?", "answer": "Jesus Christ" },
        { "question": "In which town was Jesus born?", "answer": "Bethlehem" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Jesus’ mother?", "answer": "Mary" },
        { "question": "Who was Jesus’ earthly father?", "answer": "Joseph" },
        { "question": "What guided the Wise Men to Jesus?", "answer": "A star" },
        { "question": "What gifts did the Wise Men bring to Jesus?", "answer": "Gold, Frankincense, and Myrrh" },
        { "question": "What angel told Mary she would have a baby?", "answer": "Gabriel" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the celebration 12 days after Christmas?", "answer": "Epiphany" },
        { "question": "What does the word 'Noel' mean?", "answer": "Christmas or birth" },
        { "question": "What does the Advent wreath symbolize?", "answer": "The coming of Christ" },
        { "question": "What plant is traditionally associated with kissing at Christmas?", "answer": "Mistletoe" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the carol that begins with 'God rest ye merry, gentlemen'?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry, Gentlemen" },
        { "question": "What bird is often associated with Christmas cards in the UK?", "answer": "Robin" },
        { "question": "What day follows Christmas Day?", "answer": "Boxing Day" },
        { "question": "What color are the berries on a holly plant?", "answer": "Red" },
        { "question": "What traditional dessert is set on fire during Christmas in the UK?", "answer": "Christmas pudding" },
        { "question": "Who wrote *A Christmas Carol*?", "answer": "Charles Dickens" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the main character in *A Christmas Carol*?", "answer": "Ebenezer Scrooge" },
        { "question": "What are the names of the three spirits that visit Scrooge?", "answer": "The Ghost of Christmas Past, Present, and Yet to Come" },
        { "question": "What is the traditional meat for Christmas dinner in the UK?", "answer": "Turkey" },
        { "question": "What is hidden inside a Christmas cracker?", "answer": "A joke, a paper hat, and a small gift" },
        { "question": "What do children traditionally leave out for Santa Claus in the UK?", "answer": "A mince pie and a glass of sherry" },
        { "question": "What do children traditionally leave out for Santa’s reindeer?", "answer": "Carrots" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the hymn that begins with 'Silent night, holy night'?", "answer": "Silent Night" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Christmas song about a red-nosed reindeer?", "answer": "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer" },
        { "question": "What does Santa Claus traditionally say?", "answer": "Ho ho ho!" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Santa’s sleigh-pulling team?", "answer": "Reindeer" },
        { "question": "Which reindeer is named after a weather phenomenon?", "answer": "Blitzen" },
        { "question": "What day is the first day of Advent?", "answer": "The fourth Sunday before Christmas" },
        { "question": "What is the traditional Christmas drink made with milk, cream, and eggs?", "answer": "Eggnog" },
        { "question": "Which plant is known as the 'Christmas flower'?", "answer": "Poinsettia" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Christmas story about a boy who discovers a magical train to the North Pole?", "answer": "The Polar Express" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the snowman in the song 'Frosty the Snowman'?", "answer": "Frosty" },
        { "question": "Who helps Santa in his workshop?", "answer": "Elves" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the 12-day long Christmas song?", "answer": "The Twelve Days of Christmas" },
        { "question": "What bird is given on the first day of Christmas in the song?", "answer": "A partridge in a pear tree" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the star that shone over Jesus’ birthplace?", "answer": "The Star of Bethlehem" },
        { "question": "Which country is credited with starting the Christmas tree tradition?", "answer": "Germany" },
        { "question": "What are the first words of 'We Wish You a Merry Christmas'?", "answer": "We wish you a Merry Christmas" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the building where Jesus was born?", "answer": "A stable" },
        { "question": "Who was the Roman ruler during Jesus’ birth?", "answer": "Caesar Augustus" },
        { "question": "What Christmas story features a boy left behind by his family?", "answer": "Home Alone" },
        { "question": "What kind of cake is traditionally eaten at Christmas in the UK?", "answer": "Christmas cake" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the period leading up to Christmas?", "answer": "Advent" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the snowman brought to life in a popular Christmas film?", "answer": "Jack Frost" },
        { "question": "What popular Christmas activity involves knocking on doors and singing?", "answer": "Caroling" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the reindeer with a glowing nose?", "answer": "Rudolph" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the holiday drink that shares its name with a type of log?", "answer": "Yule log" },
        { "question": "What Christmas decoration is usually hung on a door?", "answer": "Wreath" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the royal speech broadcast on Christmas Day in the UK?", "answer": "The King’s Speech" },
        { "question": "What do we call the day before Christmas?", "answer": "Christmas Eve" },
        { "question": "What Christmas-themed ballet features the 'Dance of the Sugar Plum Fairy'?", "answer": "The Nutcracker" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the donkey in the Nativity story?", "answer": "It is unnamed in the Bible but often called the 'donkey'" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the famous Christmas market in London?", "answer": "Winter Wonderland" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the movie where a young boy wishes to make his family disappear?", "answer": "Home Alone" },
        { "question": "Who was the first person to decorate a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Martin Luther" },
        { "question": "What is another name for Santa Claus in the UK?", "answer": "Father Christmas" },
        { "question": "What fruit is traditionally placed in Christmas stockings?", "answer": "Orange" },
        { "question": "What does 'X' in Xmas stand for?", "answer": "Christ" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the red Christmas flower?", "answer": "Poinsettia" },
        { "question": "What do we call the shortest day of the year, close to Christmas?", "answer": "Winter Solstice" },
        { "question": "Which saint is Santa Claus based on?", "answer": "Saint Nicholas" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the hymn that begins 'O come, all ye faithful'?", "answer": "O Come, All Ye Faithful" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the reindeer song?", "answer": "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Christmas tradition where children leave socks out?", "answer": "Stocking hanging" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the lead elf in many stories?", "answer": "Often Bernard (not biblical)" },
        { "question": "What is the traditional Christmas meat in Victorian England?", "answer": "Goose" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the night Santa delivers presents?", "answer": "Christmas Eve" },
        { "question": "What country claims to be the first to drink eggnog at Christmas?", "answer": "England" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the feast on December 26?", "answer": "Boxing Day" },
        { "question": "What do we call the gathering of people for prayers on Christmas morning?", "answer": "Christmas Mass" }
    ]
},
	{
    "name": "Star Wars",
    "questions": [
	{ "question": "What is Lukes callsign in the attack on the DeathStar?", "answer": "Red 5" },
        { "question": "What class of space fighter does Luke Skywalker fly to attack the DeathStar?", "answer": "X-Wing" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Han Solo’s ship?", "answer": "Millennium Falcon" },
        { "question": "Who is Luke Skywalker’s father?", "answer": "Darth Vader" },
        { "question": "What planet is Princess Leia from?", "answer": "Alderaan" },
        { "question": "What species is Yoda?", "answer": "Unknown" },
        { "question": "What color is Luke Skywalker’s lightsaber in *Return of the Jedi*?", "answer": "Green" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the desert planet where Luke grew up?", "answer": "Tatooine" },
        { "question": "Who is the protocol droid built by Anakin Skywalker?", "answer": "C-3PO" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Darth Vader’s original Jedi identity?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker" },
        { "question": "What is the weapon of a Jedi Knight?", "answer": "Lightsaber" },
        { "question": "What planet is the home of the Wookiees?", "answer": "Kashyyyk" },
        { "question": "Who is the bounty hunter that captured Han Solo in *The Empire Strikes Back*?", "answer": "Boba Fett" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the ice planet in *The Empire Strikes Back*?", "answer": "Hoth" },
        { "question": "Who trained Luke Skywalker in the ways of the Force?", "answer": "Yoda" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Sith Lord who manipulates Anakin Skywalker?", "answer": "Palpatine" },
        { "question": "What is the real name of the Emperor?", "answer": "Sheev Palpatine" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the group fighting against the Empire?", "answer": "The Rebel Alliance" },
        { "question": "What is the title of the first Star Wars film released?", "answer": "*Star Wars: A New Hope*" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Death Star’s main weapon?", "answer": "Superlaser" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the creature that tries to eat Luke in the trash compactor?", "answer": "Dianoga" },
        { "question": "Who says, 'I’ve got a bad feeling about this' in *A New Hope*?", "answer": "Luke Skywalker" },
        { "question": "Who is the leader of the First Order?", "answer": "Supreme Leader Snoke" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the planet destroyed by the Death Star in *A New Hope*?", "answer": "Alderaan" },
        { "question": "Who plays Han Solo?", "answer": "Harrison Ford" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the small, bear-like creatures in *Return of the Jedi*?", "answer": "Ewoks" },
        { "question": "Who is Kylo Ren’s mother?", "answer": "Leia Organa" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the podracer Anakin Skywalker pilots?", "answer": "Sebulba’s Podracer" },
        { "question": "Who is the droid that accompanies Rey in *The Force Awakens*?", "answer": "BB-8" },
        { "question": "What is Finn’s stormtrooper designation?", "answer": "FN-2187" },
        { "question": "Who kills Snoke in *The Last Jedi*?", "answer": "Kylo Ren" },
        { "question": "What is the code name of the operation to destroy the second Death Star?", "answer": "Operation Cinder" },
        { "question": "What are the giant walkers used by the Empire called?", "answer": "AT-ATs" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Han Solo’s Wookiee co-pilot?", "answer": "Chewbacca" },
        { "question": "Who are the guardians of the Jedi Temple?", "answer": "The Jedi Temple Guards" },
        { "question": "What are the small scavengers on Tatooine called?", "answer": "Jawas" },
        { "question": "Who is Luke and Leia’s mother?", "answer": "Padmé Amidala" },
        { "question": "What is the Sith homeworld called?", "answer": "Exegol" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the casino city in *The Last Jedi*?", "answer": "Canto Bight" },
        { "question": "What species is Jabba the Hutt?", "answer": "Hutt" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the leader of the Separatists?", "answer": "Count Dooku" },
        { "question": "Who pilots the X-Wing Red Five?", "answer": "Luke Skywalker" },
        { "question": "What color is Mace Windu’s lightsaber?", "answer": "Purple" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the droid commander in the Clone Wars?", "answer": "General Grievous" },
        { "question": "Who are the small, force-sensitive creatures living inside all living things?", "answer": "Midichlorians" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the clone trooper commander under Obi-Wan?", "answer": "Commander Cody" },
        { "question": "Who plays Obi-Wan Kenobi in the prequel trilogy?", "answer": "Ewan McGregor" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the fighter craft used by the Empire?", "answer": "TIE Fighter" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Mandalorian who becomes a bounty hunter?", "answer": "Din Djarin" },
        { "question": "Who says, 'Do or do not. There is no try.'?", "answer": "Yoda" },
        { "question": "Who killed Qui-Gon Jinn?", "answer": "Darth Maul" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the droid in *Rogue One*?", "answer": "K-2SO" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the weapon used by stormtroopers?", "answer": "Blaster Rifle" },
        { "question": "Who is the captain of the Millennium Falcon before Han Solo?", "answer": "Lando Calrissian" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the planet where Anakin and Obi-Wan duel?", "answer": "Mustafar" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the clone army’s creator?", "answer": "Jango Fett" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Jedi Council leader?", "answer": "Mace Windu" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Luke Skywalker’s twin sister?", "answer": "Leia Organa" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the speeder bikes on Endor?", "answer": "74-Z Speeder Bikes" },
        { "question": "Who is Anakin Skywalker’s Padawan?", "answer": "Ahsoka Tano" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Sith apprentice in *The Phantom Menace*?", "answer": "Darth Maul" },
        { "question": "Who voices Darth Vader?", "answer": "James Earl Jones" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the ship that rescues Luke at the end of *The Empire Strikes Back*?", "answer": "The Millennium Falcon" },
        { "question": "Who kills Jabba the Hutt?", "answer": "Leia Organa" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Anakin Skywalker’s starfighter?", "answer": "Delta-7 Aethersprite" },
        { "question": "Who is the leader of the Trade Federation?", "answer": "Nute Gunray" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Empire’s superweapon?", "answer": "Death Star" },
        { "question": "Who says, 'The Force will be with you. Always.'?", "answer": "Obi-Wan Kenobi" },
        { "question": "Who is the spy in the Rebel Alliance in *The Rise of Skywalker*?", "answer": "General Hux" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the battle station destroyed in *A New Hope*?", "answer": "The Death Star" },
        { "question": "Who is the Jedi Knight turned Sith Lord?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Poe Dameron’s droid?", "answer": "BB-8" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Supreme Chancellor turned Emperor?", "answer": "Palpatine" },
        { "question": "What are Kylo Ren’s stormtroopers called?", "answer": "The First Order Stormtroopers" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the creature Luke battles in Jabba’s palace?", "answer": "Rancor" },
        { "question": "Who defeats Darth Maul in *The Phantom Menace*?", "answer": "Obi-Wan Kenobi" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Han Solo’s son?", "answer": "Ben Solo (Kylo Ren)" },
        { "question": "What planet is Rey from?", "answer": "Jakku" },
        { "question": "What is the name of Leia’s adopted father?", "answer": "Bail Organa" },
        { "question": "What is the name of the Mandalorian armor’s material?", "answer": "Beskar" }
    ]
},
{
  "name": "Animal Collectives",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "What do you call a group of cows?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of lions?", "answer": "Pride" },
    { "question": "A collection of wolves is called a what?", "answer": "Pack" },
    { "question": "Birds live in family units called what?", "answer": "Flock" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for crows?", "answer": "Murder" },
    { "question": "What is a group of ravens known as?", "answer": "Unkindness" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of elephants?", "answer": "Parade" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of fish?", "answer": "School" },
    { "question": "A collection of dolphins is called a what?", "answer": "Pod" },
    { "question": "Whales live in family units called what?", "answer": "Pod" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for bees?", "answer": "Swarm" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of ants?", "answer": "Colony" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of chickens?", "answer": "Brood" },
    { "question": "A collection of ducks (on water) is called a what?", "answer": "Raft" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of ducks (in flight)?", "answer": "Skein" },
    { "question": "Geese (on land) live in family units called what?", "answer": "Gaggle" },
    { "question": "What is a group of geese (in flight) known as?", "answer": "Skein" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for horses?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of gorillas?", "answer": "Troop" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of kangaroos?", "answer": "Mob" },
    { "question": "A collection of owls is called a what?", "answer": "Parliament" },
    { "question": "Flamingos live in family units called what?", "answer": "Flamboyance" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for frogs?", "answer": "Army" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of sharks?", "answer": "Shiver" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of baboons?", "answer": "Troop" },
    { "question": "A collection of cats (domestic) is called a what?", "answer": "Clowder" },
    { "question": "Dogs (domestic) live in family units called what?", "answer": "Pack" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for ferrets?", "answer": "Business" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Crash" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of zebras?", "answer": "Dazzle" },
    { "question": "A collection of butterflies is called a what?", "answer": "Kaleidoscope" },
    { "question": "Tigers live in family units called what?", "answer": "Streak" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for hyenas?", "answer": "Cackle" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of peacocks?", "answer": "Ostentation" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of turkeys?", "answer": "Rafter" },
    { "question": "A collection of swans is called a what?", "answer": "Bevy" },
    { "question": "Snakes live in family units called what?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for eagles?", "answer": "Convocation" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of larks?", "answer": "Exaltation" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of pigeons?", "answer": "Kit" },
    { "question": "A collection of foxes is called a what?", "answer": "Skulk" },
    { "question": "Hedgehogs live in family units called what?", "answer": "Prickle" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for leopards?", "answer": "Leap" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of mice?", "answer": "Mischief" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of otters?", "answer": "Romp" },
    { "question": "A collection of parrots is called a what?", "answer": "Pandemonium" },
    { "question": "Porcupines live in family units called what?", "answer": "Prickle" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for quails?", "answer": "Covey" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of rats?", "answer": "Mischief" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of seagulls?", "answer": "Squabble" },
    { "question": "A collection of snails is called a what?", "answer": "Escargatoire" },
    { "question": "Squirrels live in family units called what?", "answer": "Scurry" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for toads?", "answer": "Knot" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of turtles?", "answer": "Bale" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of vultures?", "answer": "Wake" },
    { "question": "A collection of woodpeckers is called a what?", "answer": "Descent" },
    { "question": "Camels live in family units called what?", "answer": "Caravan" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for donkeys?", "answer": "Drove" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of moose?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of pandas?", "answer": "Embarrassment" },
    { "question": "A collection of penguins is called a what?", "answer": "Colony" },
    { "question": "Roosters live in family units called what?", "answer": "Brood" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for salamanders?", "answer": "Congress" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of stingrays?", "answer": "Fever" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of termites?", "answer": "Colony" },
    { "question": "A collection of wombats is called a what?", "answer": "Mob" },
    { "question": "Wolverines live in family units called what?", "answer": "Cohort" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for yaks?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of ibises?", "answer": "Congregation" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of jellyfish?", "answer": "Smack" },
    { "question": "A collection of lapwings is called a what?", "answer": "Deceit" },
    { "question": "Magpies live in family units called what?", "answer": "Tidings" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for newts?", "answer": "Knot" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of orangutans?", "answer": "Buffoonery" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of rooks?", "answer": "Building" },
    { "question": "A collection of seals is called a what?", "answer": "Colony" },
    { "question": "Starlings live in family units called what?", "answer": "Murmuration" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for tapirs?", "answer": "Candle" },
    { "question": "What do you call a group of sea urchins?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of vipers?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "A collection of walruses is called a what?", "answer": "Herd" },
    { "question": "Xenops (birds) live in family units called what?", "answer": "Flock" },
    { "question": "What’s the group name for zebrafish?", "answer": "Shoal" }
  ]
},
{
  "name": "Animal Homes",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "What is the term for the burrow system where wild rabbits live together?", "answer": "Warren" },
    { "question": "What is the word for a rabbit’s underground home?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What do we call the structure bees build naturally to raise young?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the man‑made structure where beekeepers keep honey bees?", "answer": "Hive" },
    { "question": "Where does a bear sleep or hibernate — what is its home called?", "answer": "Den" },
    { "question": "What do you call the cave where bats roost?", "answer": "Cave" },
    { "question": "What is the term for a fox’s home, often underground?", "answer": "Den" },
    { "question": "What do ants build as their nest?", "answer": "Anthill" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a bird’s home where it lays eggs and raises chicks?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the roost where owls live called?", "answer": "Tree hollow" },
    { "question": "What do we call the home of a wasp?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do squirrels build their nest?", "answer": "Drey" },
    { "question": "What is the underground home of a badger called?", "answer": "Sett" },
    { "question": "What do spiders spin for their home?", "answer": "Web" },
    { "question": "What is the name for the underground tunnels of moles?", "answer": "Tunnel" },
    { "question": "What do prairie dogs live in?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the coral home of reef‑building organisms called?", "answer": "Reef" },
    { "question": "Where does a penguin raise its chicks?", "answer": "Rookery" },
    { "question": "What is the term for a group of sea turtles nesting together?", "answer": "Beach nest" },
    { "question": "What do woodpeckers use as their nesting site?", "answer": "Tree cavity" },
    { "question": "Where do swallows build their nests?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nest built by eagles high in trees called?", "answer": "Eyrie" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a heron where it nests called?", "answer": "Heronry" },
    { "question": "What do termites build for their colonies?", "answer": "Mound" },
    { "question": "What is the nest of a hummingbird called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do we call the ground‑dwellings of pangolins?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a prairie owl called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do woodrats build around trees?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the hollow in which bees raise young in the wild?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do chipmunks live in?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a pair of swans called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do we call the home of penguins on ice?", "answer": "Rookery" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a barn owl called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What kind of nest do bald eagles build?", "answer": "Eyrie" },
    { "question": "Where does a robin build its nest?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the underground lair of a Tasmanian devil called?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What do voles live in?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a groundhog called?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What do hedgehogs live in?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nursery for kangaroo young inside its pouch called?", "answer": "Pouch" },
    { "question": "What do chipmunk families live in?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a puffin called?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What do we call the nesting burrow of a platypus?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the nest in tree forks for squirrels called?", "answer": "Drey" },
    { "question": "What do armadillos sleep in?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the nest of a swallow under eaves called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do prairie chickens use to raise young?", "answer": "Lekking ground" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a koel bird called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do cuckoos lay eggs?", "answer": "Nest (other birds)" },
    { "question": "What is the underground home of a gopher called?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What do rabbits use for their dens besides warrens?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the term for a fox family home?", "answer": "Den" },
    { "question": "What is the cave dwelling of bears for hibernation called?", "answer": "Den" },
    { "question": "Where do owls often rest during day?", "answer": "Tree hollow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a vulture when nesting?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do we call the barn swallow’s nest made of mud?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nesting place of a woodrat?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do bottlenose dolphins use to care for their young?", "answer": "Calf nursery (at sea)" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a kingfisher on a river bank?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the nest of a hummingbird called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do quail lay their eggs?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the underground home of a badger again?", "answer": "Sett" },
    { "question": "What do peregrine falcons use for nesting?", "answer": "Eyrie" },
    { "question": "What is the roseate spoonbill's nesting area called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where does a barnacle settle and grow?", "answer": "Shell (attached)" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a seagull on cliffs called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do albatross pairs build on the ground?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nesting structure of crocodiles called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do pelicans build their nests?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the burrow of a meerkat called?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a wren called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do we call a swallow’s home under a bridge?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where does a rocket lizard live?", "answer": "Burrow" },
    { "question": "What is the nest a weaver bird builds called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do flamingos build as a nest?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nesting location of wood storks called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do penguins build on ice?", "answer": "Rookery" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a tern on rocky islands?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What do warblers use for their homes?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the home of an osprey built on poles called?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the nesting structure of prairie owls again?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "Where do kestrels nest?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the home of an eagle near water called?", "answer": "Eyrie" },
    { "question": "What is the nesting place of wading herons?", "answer": "Heronry" },
    { "question": "What do we call the communal nesting site of gulls?", "answer": "Colony" },
    { "question": "Where do geese often nest on cliffs?", "answer": "Nest" },
    { "question": "What is the home of a tree swallow?", "answer": "Nest" }
  ]
},

{
  "name": "Ancient Egypt",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "Who was the ruler of Ancient Egypt called?", "answer": "Pharaoh" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the writing system used by Ancient Egyptians?", "answer": "Hieroglyphics" },
    { "question": "What giant river was very important to Ancient Egyptians?", "answer": "Nile" },
    { "question": "What did Egyptians build as tombs for their pharaohs?", "answer": "Pyramids" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the big stone statues with lion bodies and human heads?", "answer": "Sphinx" },
    { "question": "What animal was sacred and often worshipped in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "Cat" },
    { "question": "What was the process called where Egyptians preserved bodies?", "answer": "Mummification" },
    { "question": "What were the people called who could read and write hieroglyphics?", "answer": "Scribes" },
    { "question": "Which god had the head of a falcon and was very important?", "answer": "Horus" },
    { "question": "What was the paper made from reeds called?", "answer": "Papyrus" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian writing tool called?", "answer": "Reed pen" },
    { "question": "Which goddess was the mother of the pharaoh and goddess of fertility?", "answer": "Isis" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian sun god called?", "answer": "Ra" },
    { "question": "What color was associated with life and rebirth in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "Green" },
    { "question": "What was the purpose of the Eye of Horus symbol?", "answer": "Protection" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian underworld called?", "answer": "Duat" },
    { "question": "Which ruler was famous for his golden mask found in his tomb?", "answer": "Tutankhamun" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to build their houses?", "answer": "Mud bricks" },
    { "question": "What was the job of a vizier in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "Advisor or chief minister" },
    { "question": "Which plant grew along the Nile and was used for making papyrus?", "answer": "Reed" },
    { "question": "What festival did Ancient Egyptians celebrate to mark the flooding of the Nile?", "answer": "The Inundation" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the stone that helped decode hieroglyphics?", "answer": "Rosetta Stone" },
    { "question": "Who was the first female pharaoh?", "answer": "Hatshepsut" },
    { "question": "What kind of animal was Anubis associated with?", "answer": "Jackal" },
    { "question": "What was a common job for most Ancient Egyptians?", "answer": "Farmer" },
    { "question": "Which Ancient Egyptian god was known as the god of the dead?", "answer": "Osiris" },
    { "question": "What kind of writing surface did Ancient Egyptians invent?", "answer": "Papyrus scroll" },
    { "question": "How did Ancient Egyptians measure time during the day?", "answer": "Sundial" },
    { "question": "What was the role of a priest in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "To perform religious rituals" },
    { "question": "What animal was often mummified besides humans?", "answer": "Cats" },
    { "question": "Which Pharaoh built the Great Pyramid of Giza?", "answer": "Khufu" },
    { "question": "How long did it take to build the Great Pyramid?", "answer": "About 20 years" },
    { "question": "What was the purpose of the pyramids?", "answer": "Tombs for pharaohs" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian symbol for life?", "answer": "Ankh" },
    { "question": "What kind of jewelry did Ancient Egyptians wear?", "answer": "Beaded necklaces" },
    { "question": "What was the role of the scribe in Egyptian society?", "answer": "Record keeper and writer" },
    { "question": "What color did Ancient Egyptians use for eye makeup?", "answer": "Green and black" },
    { "question": "What was the main building material for temples in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "Stone" },
    { "question": "Which Pharaoh was famous for his extensive building projects and temples?", "answer": "Ramesses II" },
    { "question": "What was the job of a farmer in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "To grow crops and raise animals" },
    { "question": "What were the large boats called that Egyptians used to travel on the Nile?", "answer": "Papyrus boats" },
    { "question": "Which god was the judge of the dead in the afterlife?", "answer": "Osiris" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the Ancient Egyptian sun disk god?", "answer": "Aten" },
    { "question": "Which goddess protected women and children?", "answer": "Isis" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians believe happened after death?", "answer": "Life after death" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the first Ancient Egyptian capital?", "answer": "Memphis" },
    { "question": "Which animal represented the goddess Bastet?", "answer": "Cat" },
    { "question": "How many pyramids are there at Giza?", "answer": "Three" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the oldest pyramid in Egypt?", "answer": "Step Pyramid of Djoser" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to decorate tomb walls?", "answer": "Paintings and hieroglyphs" },
    { "question": "What was the purpose of the scarab beetle symbol?", "answer": "Good luck and rebirth" },
    { "question": "Who discovered King Tutankhamun’s tomb?", "answer": "Howard Carter" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the god of war and chaos?", "answer": "Set" },
    { "question": "Which god was associated with writing and knowledge?", "answer": "Thoth" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use for counting and record keeping?", "answer": "Counting boards and symbols" },
    { "question": "What was the term for the ruler’s staff or crook?", "answer": "Scepter" },
    { "question": "Which river flooded each year to fertilize the land?", "answer": "Nile" },
    { "question": "What did the Ancient Egyptians build to control the Nile’s flooding?", "answer": "Irrigation systems" },
    { "question": "What kind of clothes did Ancient Egyptians wear?", "answer": "Linen" },
    { "question": "What did the scarab beetle represent to the Egyptians?", "answer": "Rebirth and transformation" },
    { "question": "Who was the famous queen who ruled with her husband Akhenaten?", "answer": "Nefertiti" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the Ancient Egyptian goddess of truth and justice?", "answer": "Ma'at" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to make sandals?", "answer": "Papyrus and leather" },
    { "question": "What kind of animals did Egyptians keep on farms?", "answer": "Cattle, goats, and sheep" },
    { "question": "What was a common Egyptian tool for farming?", "answer": "Hoe" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the god who protected travelers?", "answer": "Anubis" },
    { "question": "What was the Egyptian god of the sky?", "answer": "Horus" },
    { "question": "How did Egyptians build the pyramids without modern machines?", "answer": "Using ramps and lots of workers" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians believe the afterlife would be like?", "answer": "A perfect and happy place" },
    { "question": "What was the mummy wrapped in?", "answer": "Linen bandages" },
    { "question": "What was the purpose of the canopic jars in mummification?", "answer": "To hold the organs" },
    { "question": "Who was the god of the desert and storms?", "answer": "Set" },
    { "question": "Which queen was famous for her beauty and ruled Egypt?", "answer": "Cleopatra" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to paint their tombs?", "answer": "Natural pigments" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the Egyptian book of spells for the afterlife?", "answer": "Book of the Dead" },
    { "question": "What did Egyptians believe the heart was used for in the afterlife?", "answer": "To be weighed for judgment" },
    { "question": "What was the symbol of the pharaoh’s power?", "answer": "The crook and flail" },
    { "question": "What were the large stone columns in temples called?", "answer": "Pillars" },
    { "question": "Who was the god of the Nile and fertility?", "answer": "Hapi" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to make jewelry?", "answer": "Gold and precious stones" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian capital during the New Kingdom?", "answer": "Thebes" },
    { "question": "What animals were often seen in Egyptian art?", "answer": "Cats, crocodiles, and scarabs" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians call their land?", "answer": "Kemet" },
    { "question": "What does the word ‘pharaoh’ mean?", "answer": "Great house" },
    { "question": "Which god was the protector of the dead?", "answer": "Anubis" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the sun god who traveled through the underworld?", "answer": "Ra" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the legendary king who united Upper and Lower Egypt?", "answer": "Narmer" },
    { "question": "What did the pyramids protect inside?", "answer": "The body and treasures of the pharaoh" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian calendar based on?", "answer": "The cycles of the moon and the Nile flood" },
    { "question": "How many days were in the Ancient Egyptian calendar?", "answer": "365 days" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians use to clean their teeth?", "answer": "Chewing sticks" },
    { "question": "What kind of music did Ancient Egyptians play?", "answer": "Harps, flutes, and drums" },
    { "question": "What was the Ancient Egyptian symbol for royalty?", "answer": "The cobra and vulture" },
    { "question": "What did Ancient Egyptians write on before papyrus was common?", "answer": "Stone and pottery" },
    { "question": "What type of animal was sacred to the god Thoth?", "answer": "Ibis" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the Ancient Egyptian goddess of love and beauty?", "answer": "Hathor" },
    { "question": "What was the main role of Ancient Egyptian women?", "answer": "Managing the household and family" },
    { "question": "What type of games did children play in Ancient Egypt?", "answer": "Board games like Senet" }
  ]
},

{
  "name": "Roman History",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "Who was the first Roman emperor?", "answer": "Augustus" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the ancient Roman army leader title?", "answer": "Consul" },
    { "question": "What large amphitheatre was built in Rome?", "answer": "Colosseum" },
    { "question": "What were the Roman roads called that still exist today?", "answer": "Via roads" },
    { "question": "Who was the Roman god of war?", "answer": "Mars" },
    { "question": "Which document gave Roman citizens certain rights?", "answer": "Twelve Tables" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the river that helped Rome grow?", "answer": "Tiber" },
    { "question": "What structure carried water into Roman cities?", "answer": "Aqueduct" },
    { "question": "What was the Roman empire's currency?", "answer": "Denarius" },
    { "question": "What building did Roman citizens go to bath and meet?", "answer": "Bathhouse" },
    { "question": "What did Romans call England?", "answer": "Britannia" },
    { "question": "Which Roman emperor built a wall in Britain?", "answer": "Hadrian" },
    { "question": "What was Hadrian’s Wall built for?", "answer": "Defence" },
    { "question": "Where were public meetings held in Rome?", "answer": "Forum" },
    { "question": "What do we call a Roman ruler who also had absolute power?", "answer": "Emperor" },
    { "question": "Who was the famous Roman soldier Julius Caesar fought?", "answer": "Pompey" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the tunnel across the River Solent?", "answer": "No evidence, false legend" },
    { "question": "What was the Roman name for London?", "answer": "Londinium" },
    { "question": "What transported clothes and goods by boat in Roman Britain?", "answer": "River barges" },
    { "question": "What was the Roman name for York?", "answer": "Eboracum" },
    { "question": "What sports did Romans watch in the Colosseum?", "answer": "Gladiator fights" },
    { "question": "What did Romans call their gods and goddesses?", "answer": "Deities" },
    { "question": "What were flat-topped peaks in Roman Britain called?", "answer": "Not Roman concept" },
    { "question": "Which Roman general invaded Britain in AD 43?", "answer": "Aulus Plautius" },
    { "question": "What were Roman soldiers called?", "answer": "Legionaries" },
    { "question": "How many men roughly formed a Roman legion?", "answer": "About 5,000" },
    { "question": "What did Roman roads have to stay straight?", "answer": "Surveyors and tools" },
    { "question": "What large gate structure did Romans build everywhere?", "answer": "Arch" },
    { "question": "What palace was built by Romans in Bath?", "answer": "Bath Temple complex" },
    { "question": "What was the name for ‘Emperor’s palace’ in Rome?", "answer": "Palatium (Palace)" },
    { "question": "What animals were used in Roman Britain for food?", "answer": "Pigs, cattle, sheep" },
    { "question": "Which Roman holiday involved wearing masks and feasts?", "answer": "Saturnalia" },
    { "question": "How did Romans keep track of time in daytime?", "answer": "Sundial" },
    { "question": "What was a Roman bath’s hot room called?", "answer": "Caldarium" },
    { "question": "Who fought Julius Caesar in the civil war?", "answer": "Pompey" },
    { "question": "What fictional creature did Romans adopt from Egyptian legend?", "answer": "Sphinx" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the teacher who had wooden tablets?", "answer": "Magister" },
    { "question": "What did Romans write on before paper? ", "answer": "Wax tablets" },
    { "question": "What was the name for the chief Roman official in a province?", "answer": "Governor (Proconsul)" },
    { "question": "What protective barriers were built around forts?", "answer": "Ditches and ramparts" },
    { "question": "What did Romano-British towns often include?", "answer": "Forum, baths, amphitheatre" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the Roman god of the sea?", "answer": "Neptune" },
    { "question": "What did Roman soldiers wear on their feet?", "answer": "Caligae (sandals)" },
    { "question": "What did Romans use to heat their floors?", "answer": "Hypocaust" },
    { "question": "Which Emperor tried to make Britain the 4th Roman province?", "answer": "Claudius" },
    { "question": "What were Roman forts in Britain called?", "answer": "Castrum" },
    { "question": "What did Romans call their Senate meeting place?", "answer": "Curia" },
    { "question": "What did Roman children play with?", "answer": "Knucklebones and dolls" },
    { "question": "What shape is a Roman amphitheatre usually?", "answer": "Oval" },
    { "question": "What was Roman leather covered writing style called?", "answer": "Caput quod aptum" },
    { "question": "Which Roman god was protector of home and family?", "answer": "Vesta" },
    { "question": "What symbolized Rome’s authority?" , "answer": "Aquila (eagle standard)" },
    { "question": "What did Romans eat for breakfast?", "answer": "Bread and cheese" },
    { "question": "What did they use to get water in their homes?", "answer": "Lead pipes" },
    { "question": "What landmarks did Romans build in their towns?", "answer": "Temples and forums" },
    { "question": "What Roman site in Northern England included baths and a temple?", "answer": "Baths at Bath city" },
    { "question": "What animal was believed to protect Roman frontiers?", "answer": "Wolf (Romulus and Remus) – myth" },
    { "question": "Which Roman emperor visited Britain in AD 122?", "answer": "Hadrian" },
    { "question": "What is Latin for 'hail, Caesar'?", "answer": "Ave Caesar" },
    { "question": "What did Romans carve gods into on buildings?", "answer": "Reliefs" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the political assembly in Rome?", "answer": "Senate" },
    { "question": "Which Roman Emperor made Christianity legal?", "answer": "Constantine" },
    { "question": "What did Roman farmers grow?", "answer": "Wheat, barley, grapes" },
    { "question": "What tool did Roman farmers use?", "answer": "Plough" },
    { "question": "What were wealthy Romans’ homes called?", "answer": "Domus" },
    { "question": "What public building did Romans use for courts?", "answer": "Basilica" },
    { "question": "Which part of Britain was never conquered by Rome?", "answer": "Scotland north of Caledonia" },
    { "question": "What piece of jewellery did Romans give to soldiers?", "answer": "Signet ring" },
    { "question": "What did Romans do to build straight roads?", "answer": "Used groma tool" },
    { "question": "Who fought in gladiator style matches?", "answer": "Gladiators" },
    { "question": "Where did gladiators fight in Rome?", "answer": "Colosseum" },
    { "question": "What protective headgear did Roman soldiers use?", "answer": "Galea (helmet)" },
    { "question": "What special cloak did Roman generals wear?", "answer": "Toga praetexta" },
    { "question": "What protected Roman towns from floods?", "answer": "Aqueduct drainage and flood walls" },
    { "question": "What form of storytelling did Romans use in plays?", "answer": "Comedy and tragedy plays" },
    { "question": "What animal was sacred to Jupiter?", "answer": "Eagle" },
    { "question": "What story did Romans tell about the city's founding?", "answer": "Romulus and Remus" },
    { "question": "What did Romans carve into stone to record events?", "answer": "Inscriptions" },
    { "question": "What did Romans use on walls to write?", "answer": "Wax tablets or ink on plaster (frescoes)" },
    { "question": "What fancy dining room did wealthy Romans have?", "answer": "Triclinium" },
    { "question": "What protective footwear did soldiers wear in muddy Britain?", "answer": "Caligae with hobnails" },
    { "question": "What did Romans build to cross rivers?", "answer": "Bridges" },
    { "question": "What tool measured angles for building roads?", "answer": "Groma" },
    { "question": "What type of wine did Romans enjoy?", "answer": "Mulsum (with honey)" }
  ]
},

{
  "name": "Tudor History",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "Who was the first Tudor king?", "answer": "Henry VII" },
    { "question": "Who was Henry VIII’s second wife?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn" },
    { "question": "How many wives did Henry VIII have?", "answer": "Six" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor queen was known as 'The Virgin Queen'?", "answer": "Elizabeth I" },
    { "question": "Which famous battle did Henry VII win to become king?", "answer": "Battle of Bosworth" },
    { "question": "What church did Henry VIII create?", "answer": "Church of England" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor monarch defeated the Spanish Armada?", "answer": "Elizabeth I" },
    { "question": "What was the name of Henry VIII's only son?", "answer": "Edward VI" },
    { "question": "Who ruled England after Henry VIII died?", "answer": "Edward VI" },
    { "question": "Which wife of Henry VIII gave birth to Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn" },
    { "question": "What religion did Mary I try to bring back?", "answer": "Catholicism" },
    { "question": "What nickname was Mary I given?", "answer": "Bloody Mary" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the ship Sir Francis Drake sailed?", "answer": "The Golden Hind" },
    { "question": "Which famous Tudor explorer sailed around the world?", "answer": "Francis Drake" },
    { "question": "What punishment was used for traitors in Tudor times?", "answer": "Beheading" },
    { "question": "What was a popular Tudor food for the rich?", "answer": "Roast swan" },
    { "question": "Where did rich Tudors live?", "answer": "Manor houses" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the theatre where Shakespeare performed?", "answer": "The Globe Theatre" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor monarch never married?", "answer": "Elizabeth I" },
    { "question": "Who was the father of Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Henry VIII" },
    { "question": "What was the name of Henry VIII’s first wife?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor king only ruled for six years?", "answer": "Edward VI" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor people use instead of forks?", "answer": "Their hands or knives" },
    { "question": "What kind of clothes did Tudor peasants wear?", "answer": "Wool and rough cloth" },
    { "question": "What kind of games did Tudor children play?", "answer": "Hoodman blind, marbles, and tag" },
    { "question": "Who was the last Tudor monarch?", "answer": "Elizabeth I" },
    { "question": "Why did Henry VIII break away from the Catholic Church?", "answer": "To divorce his wife" },
    { "question": "What did Henry VIII do to many monasteries?", "answer": "Closed them down" },
    { "question": "What was the name of Henry VIII’s favourite palace?", "answer": "Hampton Court Palace" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor queen ruled for 45 years?", "answer": "Elizabeth I" },
    { "question": "What kind of plays did Shakespeare write?", "answer": "Comedies, tragedies, and histories" },
    { "question": "Which religion did Elizabeth I follow?", "answer": "Protestantism" },
    { "question": "Which Tudor explorer looked for new lands in America?", "answer": "Walter Raleigh" },
    { "question": "What did Tudors believe about illnesses?", "answer": "Caused by bad smells or imbalanced humours" },
    { "question": "What was a common Tudor punishment for stealing?", "answer": "Being put in the stocks" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor children write with?", "answer": "Quills and ink" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor schoolboys learn?", "answer": "Latin, reading, and writing" },
    { "question": "Who built the Globe Theatre?", "answer": "The Lord Chamberlain’s Men (Shakespeare’s company)" },
    { "question": "What fruit was considered a luxury in Tudor times?", "answer": "Oranges" },
    { "question": "What was the main material used in rich Tudor clothing?", "answer": "Silk and velvet" },
    { "question": "What hairstyle did many Tudor women wear?", "answer": "French hoods or coifs" },
    { "question": "What shape did Tudor houses often have?", "answer": "E-shaped or H-shaped" },
    { "question": "What were the black-and-white Tudor houses made from?", "answer": "Timber and wattle and daub" },
    { "question": "Which disease killed many people in Tudor times?", "answer": "The plague" },
    { "question": "Where did Tudor monarchs live in London?", "answer": "The Tower of London and Whitehall Palace" },
    { "question": "What sport did Henry VIII enjoy?", "answer": "Jousting" },
    { "question": "How many of Henry VIII's wives were executed?", "answer": "Two" },
    { "question": "What was the name of the fleet Elizabeth I defeated?", "answer": "The Spanish Armada" },
    { "question": "What kind of schools did poor Tudor children attend?", "answer": "None or petty schools" },
    { "question": "Which wife gave Henry VIII a son?", "answer": "Jane Seymour" },
    { "question": "What was a popular Tudor musical instrument?", "answer": "Lute" },
    { "question": "What was the job of a jester in Tudor times?", "answer": "To entertain the king and court" },
    { "question": "Who painted portraits of the Tudor royals?", "answer": "Hans Holbein" },
    { "question": "What did Elizabeth I wear around her neck?", "answer": "A ruff" },
    { "question": "What were Tudor toilets called?", "answer": "Privies" },
    { "question": "What kind of school did rich boys attend?", "answer": "Grammar school" },
    { "question": "What type of coin was used in Tudor England?", "answer": "Groat or shilling" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor people drink instead of water?", "answer": "Ale" },
    { "question": "What was the main religion in England at the start of the Tudor period?", "answer": "Catholicism" },
    { "question": "What was the name of Elizabeth I’s cousin who was executed?", "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots" },
    { "question": "What symbol is often used to represent the Tudors?", "answer": "Tudor Rose" },
    { "question": "What does the Tudor Rose combine?", "answer": "Red rose of Lancaster and white rose of York" },
    { "question": "Which house did the Tudors defeat to take the throne?", "answer": "House of York" },
    { "question": "How old was Edward VI when he became king?", "answer": "Nine" },
    { "question": "Who ruled England after Elizabeth I?", "answer": "James I" },
    { "question": "What role did Shakespeare have at the theatre?", "answer": "Actor and playwright" },
    { "question": "What food did poor Tudors often eat?", "answer": "Pottage" },
    { "question": "What was the job of a Tudor executioner?", "answer": "To carry out beheadings" },
    { "question": "What did rich Tudors use to keep warm?", "answer": "Fur and heavy curtains" },
    { "question": "What was the name of Henry VIII’s older brother?", "answer": "Arthur" },
    { "question": "Where did the Spanish Armada sail from?", "answer": "Spain" },
    { "question": "What was the favourite drink at Tudor feasts?", "answer": "Mead or ale" },
    { "question": "What building was the centre of Tudor government?", "answer": "The Royal Court" },
    { "question": "Who was Elizabeth I’s famous spymaster?", "answer": "Sir Francis Walsingham" },
    { "question": "What was used instead of soap in Tudor times?", "answer": "Ashes or herbs" },
    { "question": "Who led the rebellion against Mary I?", "answer": "Thomas Wyatt" },
    { "question": "Where was the Spanish Armada defeated?", "answer": "Off the coast of England" },
    { "question": "What did Elizabeth I do to help protect England?", "answer": "Built a strong navy" },
    { "question": "What language were church services changed to under Elizabeth I?", "answer": "English" },
    { "question": "What colour symbolised royalty in Tudor times?", "answer": "Purple" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the church Henry VIII created?", "answer": "The Church of England" },
    { "question": "What kind of roof did most Tudor homes have?", "answer": "Thatched" },
    { "question": "What disease did Henry VIII likely suffer from later in life?", "answer": "Type II diabetes or leg ulcers" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor people do for fun?", "answer": "Dancing, feasts, and watching plays" },
    { "question": "Who was the last wife of Henry VIII?", "answer": "Catherine Parr" },
    { "question": "What book helped spread Protestant ideas?", "answer": "The Bible in English" },
    { "question": "What did Tudor sailors use to navigate?", "answer": "Compass and astrolabe" },
    { "question": "Which country was often at war with Tudor England?", "answer": "France" },
    { "question": "What food was brought back from the Americas?", "answer": "Potatoes and tomatoes (though not common yet)" },
    { "question": "What law allowed Henry VIII to be head of the Church?", "answer": "Act of Supremacy" }
  ]
},

{
  "name": "AustraliaFactsQuiz",
  "questions": [
    { "question": "What is the capital city of Australia?", "answer": "Canberra" },
    { "question": "What do people call someone from Australia?", "answer": "Australian" },
    { "question": "Which ocean lies to the east of Australia?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean" },
    { "question": "What is the large desert in central Australia called?", "answer": "The Outback" },
    { "question": "What is the famous rock formation in the Outback?", "answer": "Uluru" },
    { "question": "Which reef is found off the north-east coast of Australia?", "answer": "Great Barrier Reef" },
    { "question": "What is the national animal symbol of Australia?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
    { "question": "What small jumping marsupial is also on Australia's coat of arms?", "answer": "Emu" },
    { "question": "Which city is famous for its Opera House?", "answer": "Sydney" },
    { "question": "What inhabitant of Australia carries its baby in a pouch?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
    { "question": "Which animal is famous for carrying koalas on its back?", "answer": "Eucalyptus trees" },
    { "question": "What is Australia’s largest city by population?", "answer": "Sydney" },
    { "question": "What do Australians call a barbecue?", "answer": "Barbie" },
    { "question": "What climate is found in the northern part of Australia?", "answer": "Tropical" },
    { "question": "Which large island state lies south-east of Australia?", "answer": "Tasmania" },
    { "question": "What is the longest river in Australia?", "answer": "Murray River" },
    { "question": "Which Australian city hosts a famous harbour bridge?", "answer": "Sydney" },
    { "question": "What kind of animal is a platypus?", "answer": "Monotreme" },
    { "question": "Which bird is known for its laughing call and lives in Australia?", "answer": "Kookaburra" },
    { "question": "What wallaby relative hops from tree to tree?", "answer": "Tree kangaroo" },
    { "question": "Which deadly insect is native to Australia?", "answer": "Sydney funnel-web spider" },
    { "question": "What is the national gemstone of Australia?", "answer": "Opal" },
    { "question": "What is the tallest mountain in Australia?", "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko" },
    { "question": "Which plant is Australia’s floral emblem?", "answer": "Golden wattle" },
    { "question": "What is a male kangaroo called?", "answer": "Boomer" },
    { "question": "What is the name for a group of kangaroos?", "answer": "Mob" },
    { "question": "Which reef can be seen from space?", "answer": "Great Barrier Reef" },
    { "question": "What is the capital city of Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane" },
    { "question": "What is the name of Australia’s currency?", "answer": "Australian dollar" },
    { "question": "What year did Australia become a federation?", "answer": "1901" },
    { "question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Australia?", "answer": "Edmund Barton" },
    { "question": "Which animal lays eggs and is native to Australia?", "answer": "Echidna" },
    { "question": "What endangered marsupial looks like a pig?", "answer": "Numbat" },
    { "question": "Which city is known as the cultural heart of Australia?", "answer": "Melbourne" },
    { "question": "What famous fence separates the southern and northern climates?", "answer": "The Dingo Fence" },
    { "question": "Which sand island is the world’s largest?", "answer": "Fraser Island" },
    { "question": "What is the driest inhabited continent?", "answer": "Australia" },
    { "question": "What continent is Australia on?", "answer": "Australia" },
    { "question": "Which lake turns pink due to algae?", "answer": "Lake Hillier" },
    { "question": "What is a baby kangaroo called?", "answer": "Joey" },
    { "question": "Which marsupial is known for its black-and-white stripes?", "answer": "Tasmanian devil" },
    { "question": "Which large bird is known for its fast running?", "answer": "Emu" },
    { "question": "What plant is known as the boab in Western Australia?", "answer": "Baobab tree" },
    { "question": "Which festival happens on New Year’s Eve in Australia?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour fireworks" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the desert in Western Australia?", "answer": "Great Victoria Desert" },
    { "question": "Which animal’s call sounds like laughter?", "answer": "Kookaburra" },
    { "question": "What do Australians often call their countryside?", "answer": "The Outback" },
    { "question": "Which island is home to the Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Tasmania" },
    { "question": "Which national park has the famous sandstone domes known as the Bungle Bungles?", "answer": "Purnululu National Park" },
    { "question": "Which river flows through Darwin?", "answer": "Daly River" },
    { "question": "Which sea lies to the west of Australia?", "answer": "Indian Ocean" },
    { "question": "What Aboriginal instrument is a long wooden wind instrument?", "answer": "Didgeridoo" },
    { "question": "Which reef is home to 1,500 species of fish?", "answer": "Great Barrier Reef" },
    { "question": "What endangered marsupial is found in the wet tropics?", "answer": "Tree kangaroo" },
    { "question": "What iconic rock in Northern Territory is also called Ayers Rock?", "answer": "Uluru" },
    { "question": "Which Australian poet wrote 'Waltzing Matilda'?", "answer": "Banjo Paterson" },
    { "question": "Which Australian animal is also called 'the dog of the bush'?", "answer": "Dingo" },
    { "question": "What is celebrated on Australia Day?", "answer": "Federation (January 26)" },
    { "question": "Which bird can mimic human speech in Australia?", "answer": "Lyrebird" },
    { "question": "What mountain range runs along the east coast?", "answer": "Great Dividing Range" },
    { "question": "Which state is also a giant island?", "answer": "Tasmania" },
    { "question": "Which native tree has spiky leaves and red flowers near Christmas?", "answer": "Christmas tree (Nuytsia floribunda)" },
    { "question": "What is the red centre of Australia called?", "answer": "Red Centre" },
    { "question": "Which bat can 'see' with its ears?", "answer": "Microbat" },
    { "question": "Which large salt lake turns bright pink?", "answer": "Lake Hillier" },
    { "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Australia?", "answer": "Wallaman Falls" },
    { "question": "Which mine is in the Olympic Dam region?", "answer": "Roxby Downs" },
    { "question": "What desert lies around Alice Springs?", "answer": "Simpson Desert" },
    { "question": "Which animal is known as the 'laughing jackass'?", "answer": "Kookaburra" },
    { "question": "What do camels in Australia come from?", "answer": "Introduced by Europeans" },
    { "question": "Which Aboriginal art symbol shows people meeting?", "answer": "Concentric circles" },
    { "question": "What is the name of Australia's national airline?", "answer": "Qantas" },
    { "question": "Which animal has a bill like a duck and lays eggs?", "answer": "Platypus" },
    { "question": "Who was the first European to reach Australia?", "answer": "Willem Janszoon (1606)" },
    { "question": "Which explorer charted the Australian coast for Britain?", "answer": "Captain James Cook" },
    { "question": "What did the First Fleet bring to Australia?", "answer": "Convicts" },
    { "question": "Which city is famous for its harbour and opera house?", "answer": "Sydney" },
    { "question": "What is Australia’s national anthem?", "answer": "Advance Australia Fair" },
    { "question": "What colour are most Australian gum trees?", "answer": "Grey or white" },
    { "question": "Which sport is played on oval fields in Australia?", "answer": "Australian Rules Football" },
    { "question": "What Olympic Games did Australia host in 2000?", "answer": "Sydney 2000 Olympics" },
    { "question": "Which famous Tasmanian landmark is named 'The Wall'?", "answer": "Cradle Mountain Walls" },
    { "question": "Which famous rock formation is in the Kimberley region?", "answer": "Horizontal Falls" },
    { "question": "What is the name of the Australian currency symbol?", "answer": "$" },
    { "question": "Which animal is featured on the Australian 1-dollar coin?", "answer": "Kangaroo" },
    { "question": "Which surf town is known as the 'Big Banana'?", "answer": "Coffs Harbour" },
    { "question": "What type of climate is in southern Australia?", "answer": "Temperate" },
    { "question": "What famous road trip route runs from Sydney to Melbourne?", "answer": "Princes Highway" },
    { "question": "What protective sunscreen do Australians call 'sunnies'?", "answer": "Sunglasses" }
  ]
}







]
